# YOONJOO LEE

#### yoonjoo.lee@kaist.ac.kr | yoonjoolee.com

#### **RESEARCH INTEREST**

My research interest lies in the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI) and natural language processing (NLP). I aim to help diverse users reach meaningful understanding by connecting new information to what they already know. I'm particularly interested in creating systems that guide AI agents to generate outputs aligned with human knowledge acquisition processes, thereby reducing the gap between the support humans need and the explanations AI agents provide.

#### **EDUCATION**

KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science. Advisor: Juho Kim

Sep. 2020 – Present

Ewha Womans University Seoul, Republic of Korea

M.S. in Statistics (Applicational Statistics). Advisor: Dongwan Shin

Mar. 2018 – Feb. 2020

B.S. Major in Mathematics Education, Minor in Statistics; *Magna Cum Laude*Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA, USA

Exchange student in Mathematics Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Adobe Research San Jose, US

Research Intern, Document Intelligence Lab May 2024 ~ Present

Mentor: Alexa F Siu, Tong Sun

Allen Institute for AI (AI2) Seattle, US

Research Scientist Intern, Semantic Scholar Team
May - Oct. 2023
Mentor: Pao Siangliulue, Joseph Chee Chang, Jonathan Bragg, Kyle Lo

[C10]

1 Tuo Sainginaide, 1886pii Chee Chang, 1814bii 28

LG AI Research Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern, Advanced Machine Learning Lab
Mentor: Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee

[C6]

KIXLAB, KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Intern

Mar. 2020 – Aug. 2020

Mentor: Juho Kim, Jean Y. Song

Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Assistant, Data Sciences Group
Mentor: Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park
Mar. 2018 – Dec. 2019
[P1, P2, C1, C2]

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Conference and Journal Papers**

[C11] One vs. Many: Comprehending Accurate Information from Multiple Erroneous and Inconsistent AI Generations

Yoonjoo Lee, Kihoon Son, Tae Soo Kim, Jisu Kim, John Joon Young Chung, Eytan Adar, Juho Kim

FAccT 2024: Proceedings of the 2024 ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency.

# [C10] PaperWeaver: Enriching Topical Paper Alerts by Contextualizing Recommended Papers with User-collected Papers

**Yoonjoo Lee**, Hyeonsu B Kang, Matt Latzke, Juho Kim, Jonathan Bragg, Joseph Chee Chang, Pao Siangliulue *CHI 2024: Proceedings of the 2024 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*.

# [C9] EvalLM: Interactive Evaluation of Large Language Model Prompts on User-Defined Criteria

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Jamin Shin, Young-Ho Kim, Juho Kim

CHI 2024: Proceedings of the 2024 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

#### [C8] VIVID: Human-AI Collaborative Authoring of Vicarious Dialogues from Lecture Videos

Seulgi Choi, Hyewon Lee, Yoonjoo Lee, Juho Kim

CHI 2024: Proceedings of the 2024 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

## [C7] QASA: Advanced Question Answering on Scientific Articles

**Yoonjoo Lee**\*, Kyungjae Lee\*, Sunghyun Park, Dasol Hwang, Jaehyeon Kim, Hong-in Lee, Moontae Lee *ICML 2023: Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Machine Learning* 

# [C6] Cells, Generators, and Lenses: Design Framework for Object-Oriented Interaction with Large Language Models

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

UIST 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology.

## [C5] DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-Step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Sundong Kim, Yohan Yun, Juho Kim

CHI 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

# [C4] Promptiverse: Scalable Generation of Scaffolding Prompts Through Human-AI Hybrid Knowledge Graph Annotation

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Tae Soo Kim, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

CHI 2022: Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

# [C3] Personalizing Ambience and Illusionary Presence: How People Use "Study with Me" Videos to Create Effective Studying Environments

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Jean Y. Song, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

CHI 2021: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

# [C2] A Machine Learning Approach that meets Axiomatic Properties in Probabilistic Analysis of LTE Spectral Efficiency

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

ICTC, Oct. 2019

### [C1] Probabilistic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE based on PDCCH Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Yeonkyu Park, Seungken Park

IEEE Communications Letters, vol. 23, no. 9, Sep. 2019

## **Priprints**

# [A1] The BiGGen Bench: A Principled Benchmark for Fine-grained Evaluation of Language Models with Language Models

Seungone Kim, Juyoung Suk, Ji Yong Cho, [18 authors], **Yoonjoo Lee**, [5 authors], Sean Welleck, Graham Neubig, Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee, Minjoon Seo

Under Review, 2024

#### **Posters and Workshop Papers**

# [P5] LMCanvas: Object-Oriented Interaction to Personalize Large Language Model-Powered Writing Environments

Tae Soo Kim, Arghya Sarkar, **Yoonjoo Lee**, Minsuk Chang, and Juho Kim *CHI 2023 Workshop on Generative AI and HCI* 

# [P4] Interactive Children's Story Rewriting Through Parent-Children Interaction

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

ACL 2022 Workshop on Intelligent and Interactive Writing Assistant

#### [P3] XDesign: Integrating Interface Design into Explainable AI Education

Hyungyu Shin, Nabila Sindi, **Yoonjoo Lee**, Jaeryoung Ka, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim *SIGCSE TS 2022 Posters* 

#### [P2] A Study on the Distribution Analysis of LTE Resource Block Usage from TSME Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

# [P1] A Study on the Estimation of Probability Distribution of the Spectral Efficiency of LTE based on TSME Measurement Data

Yunbae Kim, **Yoonjoo Lee**, Seungken Park *KICS*, *Jun.* 2018

#### **ACADEMIC SERVICES**

## **Program Committee**

• CHI LBW 2023

#### **Workshop Organizing Committee**

• 2024 ACL Science Document Processing Workshop

#### Reviewer

- EMNLP 2023
- CHI 2024, 2023, 2022
- UIST 2022, 2023, 2024
- ACL 2023
- CSCW 2023
- C&C 2022, 2024
- IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies

#### **Student Volunteer**

CHI 2022

# **TEACHING**

Introduction to Algorithms Spring 2024

KAIST CS300, Instructor: Sunghee Choi

#### Introduction to Data Science Spring 2022

KAIST CS492, Instructor: Jaegil Lee

Introduction to Social Computing

KAIST CS473, Instructor: Juho Kim

**Time Series Analysis** Spring 2019 Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Dongwan Shin Fall 2018 **Regression Analysis** Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Donghwan Lee **INVITED TALKS** Invited Talk at HCI KOREA 2024: SIGCHI-Sponsored Top Conferences Session Jan. 2024 Title: DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions Technical Talk at NAVER AI LAB Nov. 2023 Title: Creating Interactive Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions **Invited Talk at UCSD Design Lab** Oct. 2023 Title: Adapting Scaffolding to Support Knowledge Consumption through Interactive AI-Driven Systems HONORS, AWARDS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS 2024 **Best Presentation Award from SIGCHI Invited Papers Session** SIGCHI Korea Local Chapter **Research Assistant Scholarship** 2019 College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University 2018 **Admission Scholarship** College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017 **Honors Scholarship** College of Education, Ewha Womans University **Dean's List** 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017 College of Education, Ewha Womans University **Ewha Womans University Alumnae Association Scholarship** 2017 College of Education, Ewha Womans University SERVICE AND LEADERSHIP **KAIST-Google ExploreCSR** 2022 Student Organizer 2016 - 2017**Programming Mentoring** Leader of Student Organizer